Finding Aid for the Ho Young Ham Papers LSC.0697
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 9: Printed materials, ca. 1905-1982; 1 box.
  - Subseries 9A: Ephemera, ca. 1908-1982
    - Korean National Association--Receipt for bearer bond 294, Korean Independence Movement., 1919 December.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 8)
      Value of bearer bond was $25. Receipt was to Mr. Ham, funds were sent to Syngman Rhee in Washington, D.C.
    - Korean National Association--Receipt for oval stamp for Korean National Association., 1938 June 13.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Korean National Association--Receipt for the traveling expenses for Dr. Syngman Rhee., 1918 December 23.; Notations on verso. (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Korean National Association--Receipts for annual fee payment., 1914-1919.; 3 items. (Box 40, Folder 11)
      Receipts in the amount of $5.00 each. Front with decorated border and Korean text. Verso in English. One signed by Syngman Rhee.
    - Korean National Association--Receipts for education donations., 1911-1919.; 9 items. (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Korean National Association--Receipts for Korean independence movement donations., 1919 May-November.; 13 items. (Box 40, Folder 13)
      Korean text. Ornamental borders and some with official stamps. Printed in Hawaii.
    - Korean National Association--Receipts for miscellaneous items., ca. 1931.; 3 items. (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Korean National Associations receipt for Ho Young Ham regarding Syngman Rhee diplomatic mission to Washington, D.C., undated.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Korean Pacific Press--"Dr. Syngman Rhee, the President of the Republic of Korea (a short biographical sketch)"., 1954 March 1.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Korean Pacific Press--Article, "Korea: Religion"., ca. 1954.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Korean Pacific Press--Article, "Korean Contributions to Civilization"., ca. 1954.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Korean Pacific Press--Articles, "Korean Folk Lore" and "The Year in Korea" by Dorothy Lewis Kinsman., ca. 1954.; 2 items. (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Korean Pacific Press--Newsletter with various articles and full-page color map of Korea., ca. 1954.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Korean Pacific Press--Newsletter with various articles and stories., ca. 1954.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Korean Pacific Press--Pantomime, "The Vanity of the Rat"., ca. 1954.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 22)
      Based on a folk story from the book, "Tales from Korea."
    - Korean Pacific Press--Sheet music, "Songs of Korea"., ca. 1954.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 23)
      Includes "Arirang," "Korean National Anthem," and "Koltak! Koltak!"
    - Korean-American news bulletin, volume 1, number 42., 1961 December 18.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - Obituaries for Ho Young Ham., 1954 March.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 25)
      Photocopied amalgamation of obituary clippings for Ho Young Ham.
    - Personal income tax receipts for Ho Young Ham., 1906-1931.; 19 items. (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - Prince of Korea, matted newsprint clipping., undated.; B/w matted print. (Box 40, Folder 27)
    - Receipt for certificate of Hawaiian birth for [unknown child]., 1928 December 7.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 28)
      Paid by Ho Young Ham.
    - Receipt for certificate of Hawaiian birth for Dora Ham and John Ham., 1936 March 17.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 29)
    - Receipt for certificate of Hawaiian birth for Norman Ham., 1928 December 7.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 30)
      Paid by Norman Ham.
    - Receipt for certificate of Hawaiian birth for Salome Ham and Mary Ham., 1928 December 7.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 31)
    - Receipt for tax clearance signed by Norman Ham., 1933 December 11.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 32)
    - Receipt from Hawaiian Commercial & Sugar Co's Camp One Store, Sprecklesville, Maui., 1935 February 16.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 33)
      Clothing for Ham, H.Y.
    - Receipts from the Kahului Garage for "Mr. Norman Hahm"., 1939 July-August.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 34)
    - Red Cross flyer--"Give to Hawaii's Tidal Wave Victims"., undated.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 35)
    - Stamp collector's stock book., undated.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 36)
      Five pages (75 lots) of stamps from worldwide locations.
    - Statements addressed to Ho Young Ham from Camp 1 Store., 1941 February 28, 1941 March 31.; 2 items. (Box 40, Folder 37)
    - Statements of employee earnings and payroll deductions for Ho Young Ham from Hawaiian Commercial and Sugar Co., 1941 January-February.; 2 items. (Box 40, Folder 38)
    - Poster--composite of various black and white photographs and newspapers articles of Korean people and events., ca. 1960.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Captions in English.
    - Poster--composite of various black and white photographs of Korean people and events., ca. 1960.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 4)
      Includes images of Syngman Rhee and his wife and the Korean military. Captions for images in Korean.
    - Newspaper--Korean National Herald., 1954 January 27.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Korean war songs., undated.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Mailing wrapper covered with Korean postage stamps., 1955 May 12.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 11)
      From a package sent by Tai Young Hahm to Clara Ham Cabrinha.
  - Subseries 9B: Maps, ca. 1956
    Four maps. Includes two maps of Korea, one of land deeded to the Korean Benevolent Society in Hawaii, and the one that appears to be a child's educational map.
    - Korean Benevolent Society map showing the location of deeded land., undated.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 39)
    - Unidentified, entitled "Elementary Map"., undated.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 40)
      Possibly of England; major towns mentioned are Oxford, Boling, York, and Salem.
    - Korean peninsula [?]., undated.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Republic of Korea color map., 1956.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 13)
      Printed in Seoul, Korea.
  - Subseries 9C: Records and certificates, ca. 1905-1979
    Ho Young Ham's ministerial licenses, various education certificates and diplomas, and other official records.
    - Certificate of birth for [Norman] Noma Ham., 1963 May 16.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 41)
      Photostat copy of "unrecorded birth" documentation from 1921 May 6, embossed with seal of state.
    - Certificate of citizenship for Suney Ham Ow., 1933 July 15.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 42)
    - Certificate of death for Hannah Ham., 1979 August 30.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 43)
      Certified copy of the original.
    - Certificate of Hawaiian birth for Chumsuney Ham., 1929 January 31.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 44)
      Headshot of Chumsuney Ham affixed to the certificate.
    - Certificate of Hawaiian birth for Suney Ham., 1924 June 16.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 45)
      Headshot of Suney Ham affixed to the certificate.
    - Exhorter's licenses for Ho Young Ham., 1923-1926.; 4 items. (Box 40, Folder 46)
      Annual licenses.
    - Honorable discharge from the National Guard for Norman Ham., 1940 March 3.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 47)
    - Korean Benevolent Society of Maui--Deed from Wailuku Sugar Company to Korean Benevolent Society of Maui., 1934 November 2.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 48)
    - Korean Benevolent Society of Maui--License to cover expenses for a farewell dinner for Kee Hong Park., 1943 July 28.; Photocopies. (Box 40, Folder 49)
    - Korean National Association donation certificates for Korean independence movement., 1919 July-August.; 3 items. (Box 40, Folder 50)
      Illustrated with Korean and American flags. Embossed with Korean National Association stamp. Nos. 797, 974, 975.
    - Korean National Association membership certificate for Ho Young Ham., 1909 February 1.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 51)
      Membership certificate no. 15. 8x10 with ornamental blue border and Korean flag surrounded by four heart-shaped symbols.
    - Korean National Association regarding provisional Korean government announcement in China., 1937.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 52)
      Overseas census request; official document.
    - Local preacher's license for the Methodist Episcopal Church for Ho Young Ham., 1923 March 24.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 53)
    - Local preacher's license for the Methodist Episcopal Church for Ho Young Ham., 1930 March 24.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 54)
    - National Service Life Insurance certificate for Norman Noma Ham in the amount of $2,000., 1941 August 29.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 55)
    - Notice of selection under the Selective Training and Service Act of 1940 for Norman Ham., 1941 June 16.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 56)
    - Office of Research, Planning & Statistics, Department of Health, Territory of Hawaii--record request., 1963 April 25.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 57)
      Request for copy of Norman's birth certificate to expedite his daughter's entrance to U.S. from Korea.
    - Order to report for induction for Norman Ham., 1941 June 18.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 58)
      Order no. V. 724.
    - Pre-nursing course completion certificate for Clara Ham., 1935 June 13.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 59)
    - Special vocational certificate for Clara Chumsuney Ham., 1938 September 1.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 60)
    - Vocational diploma for Suney E. Ham., 1928 June 5.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Grammar school diploma for Suney Ham., 1924 June 20.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - High school certificate for John Ham., 1939 June 4.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - High school certificate for Clara C. Ham., 1932 June 10.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Junior high school certificate Clara Ham., 1929 June 7.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Vocational diploma for Clara Chun Suney Ham., 1939 June 6.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Vocational diploma for Norman Hahm [Ham]., 1929 June 3.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Maui high school certificate for Suney Eleanor Ham., 1928 June 8.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Passports from the Imperial Korean Foreign Office, one for Ye Seung Kim and three blank., ca. 1905.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 9)
      Text in English, French, and Korean.
    - Certificate of marriage for Manuel Cabrinha and Clara C. Ham., 1952 July 18.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 10)